[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我们讨论了解析和生成树。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: We talked about parsing and making trees.
这是一些HTML文本。
So this is some HTML text.
这是一棵它扩展成的树
This is a tree that it expands into and
关于这一点，有一些有趣的事情需要观察。
there are some interesting things to observe about this.
一个是首先我们这里有小写的，这里有大写的。
One is first we've got lowercase here and uppercase here.
所以当网络刚开始的时候，第一代站长输入他们的
So when the web first started, the first generation of webmasters typed their
标记都是大写的，因为他们想脱颖而出。
markup all in upper case cuz they wanted to stand out.
他们想让加价变得非常明显
They wanted make it really obvious what was markup and
什么是内容，并且全部用大写字母书写使这一点更加清楚。
what was content, and writing it all in uppercase made that clearer.
几年后，他们厌倦了依靠Shift键
After a few years of that, they got tired of leaning on the Shift key and
他们决定什么见鬼了，现在都是小写了。
they decided what the hell and it's all lowercase now.
这个转变发生在Brendon设计DOM的时候。
That transition happened just as Brendon was designing the DOM.
所以DOM必须选择一个约定和约定
And so the DOM had to pick a convention and the convention
让我们用大写字母，因为那是当时人们使用的。
was let's go with uppercase because that's what people were using at the time.
所以这里所有小写的东西都会上移到那里的大写字母。
So everything that's lowercase here gets shifted up to uppercase there.
你需要意识到这一点，因为有时候这并不重要，但是
And you need to be aware of that because sometimes it doesn't matter but
有时候确实很重要。
sometimes it does matter.
所以你需要注意。
So you need to be aware.
然后在树中有文本中没有的特征。
Then there are features in the tree that are not in the text.
例如，我没有指定head标记，但树中有head标记。
For example, I did not specify a head tag, but there is a head tag in the tree.
所以它会向标记中添加额外的位。
So it'll add extra bits to the markup.
我们要做的另一个地方是在一张桌子上。
Another place we'll do that is in a table.
如果你不指定一个tbody，它会为你插入一个tbody。
If you don't specify a tbody, it'll stick a tbody in there for you.
如果你试图分析事物，这可能会给你带来麻烦，
And that can get you into trouble if you're trying to parse around things,
你会发现你没有料到的内容水平。
and you'll find levels of content that you didn't expect to find.
然后，这里的另一件事是，这是理想的Microsoft树。
Then the other thing here is that this is the ideal Microsoft tree.
所以微软IE6会制作这样一棵树。
So Microsoft IE6 would make a tree like this one.
W3C在SGL社区的影响下说不，
W3C under the influence of the SGL community said no,
你需要更多的东西。
you need to have more stuff than that.
例如，此处和之间的空格
For example the whitespace between here and
在这里，你通常会忽略它，它必须进入树中。
here, which you would ordinarily ignore, that has to go into the tree.
微软正确地决定，
Microsoft correctly decided,
不，我们不应该那样做，因为那只是浪费空间。
no we shouldn't do that because that's just a waste of space.
但其他人都这么做了，现在微软也这么做了，每个人都这么做了。
But everybody else did and now Microsoft did, everybody does that.
但我选择了微软树，因为真正的树太多毛了
But I went with Microsoft tree because the real tree is too hairy and
这很难谈论，所以我选择了更简单的树。
it's hard to talk about, so I'm going with the simpler tree instead.
这里面有一些隐含的层级。
Then there's some implied hierarchy in this.
例如，你有h1，h2和
For example, you've got h1, h2 and
它看起来有点像H2从属于H1。
it kind of looks like the h2 is subordinate to h1.
P从属于此，但它们不是。
And the Ps are subordinate to that, but they're not.
它们都在树上的同一层。
They're all at the same level in the tree.
所以你需要意识到这一点。
So you need to be aware of that.
然后在JavaScript端，在浏览器中，
Then on the JavaScript side, in the browser,
有一个称为document的全局变量，它是树的根。
there is a global variable called document, which is the root of the tree.
而document.body是访问Body节点的快捷方式。
And document.body is a shortcut for getting to the body node.
还有一个快捷方式
There is also a shortcut for
到达HTML节点，称为文档元素。
getting to the HTML node, which is called document element.
哪一个是你的东西可以叫做HTML对吗？
Which is your thing can be called HTML right?
因为它属于那个。
Cuz it goes to that one.
而不是的原因是因为在创建文档元素时，
And the reason it isn't is because at the time that document element was created,
W3C计划终止HTML和
W3C was planning to kill HTML and
他们不想把证据留在DOM里
they didn't want to leave that evidence in the DOM.
所以他们用了一个更长的名字，这样就没有人会知道了。
So they went with a longer name, so that no one would know.
但是那个阴谋没有起作用。
But that plot didn't work.
所以这是同一棵树的一个子集，
So this is a subset of the same tree,
我把它转到一边来演示下一件事。
I turned it sideways to demonstrate the next thing.
因此每个节点都有指向其他节点的指针。
So each node has pointers to other nodes.
例如，每个节点都有第一个子节点和最后一个子节点。
For example, each node has a first child and a last child node.
指向孩子们。
Which points to the children.
这些是被忽视的中间儿童，他们得不到指示。
These are neglected middle children, they don't get pointers.
那么每个P节点都只有一个子节点，所以
Then each of those P node only has one child, so
两个指针都指向同一个元素。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：那么
both pointers point to the same element. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Then
存在兄弟指针、下一个兄弟指针和前一个兄弟指针
there are sibling pointers, next sibling and previous sibling when at that way
body将与head标记具有兄弟关系。
the body will have a sibling relationship with the head tag.
这些人是表亲，你会很高兴知道没有表亲
These guys are cousins, and you'll be glad to know there are no cousin
指针。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：那就有了
pointers. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Then there is
上升的父节点指针。
the parent node pointer which goes up.
主体将有一个转到html的父节点。
The body will have a parent node going to html.
HTML将上升到文档根目录。
HTML will go up to the document root.
而且你可能会变得高贵，这是一个很多的指针。
And you might be going lordy that's a lot of pointers.
所以如果我编辑这个树，我是否必须更新所有这些指针，
So if I edit this tree, do I have to update all those pointers,
可能有点毛茸茸的。
that could be kinda hairy.
答案是否定的，事实上你不能编辑树。
And the answer is no, that in fact you cannot edit the tree.
从你的角度来看，这些都是只读的，
These are all read only from your perspective,
如果要编辑此树，则必须使用DOMAPI。
you have to use the DOM API if you want to edit this tree.
稍后我将向您展示该API。
And I'll show you that API in a moment.
现在如果结果是您想要做的就是遍历树，因为
Now if it turns out all you want to do is traverse the tree, for
例如，如果您想要访问显示顺序中的每个节点。
example if you want to visit every node in display order.
你不需要这些指点，对吧？
You don't need all these pointers, right?
如果你理解递归的工作原理，你只需要一个二叉树，对吗？
If you understand how recursion works, you only need a binary tree, right?
你可以用两个指针做到这一点。
You can make that with two pointers.
所以我可以使用第一个孩子，下一个兄弟姐妹，和一个遍历DOM函数。
So I can use first child the next sibling with a walk the DOM function.
它是一个递归函数，它知道如何进行遍历。
It's recursive function which knows how to do that traversal.
这允许我做一些事情，比如实现按名称获取元素。
And that allows me to do things like implement get elements by name.
通过传入一个函数，该函数将查找名称并将内容编译成列表。
By passing in a function which will look for names and compile things into a list.
除了所有这些指针之外，每个节点还具有一个子节点列表
In addition to all of those pointers, each node also has a list of child nodes
这有点像一个数组，其中包含所有的孩子。
which is kind of like an array which will have all of the children in it.